<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="chapter.2">
	<title>An Introduction to TestLink</title>
	
	<para>TestLink is an open source test management tool written in PHP. In 
	order to install TestLink you will need a http server with PHP 5 and a 
	database. The databases currently supported by TestLink out of the box are 
	MySQL, Postgre SQL and MS SQL, although there are users that managed to use 
	Oracle too. You can download it from <ulink url="http://www.teamst.org">
	http://www.teamst.org</ulink>.</para>
	
	<para>
		<mediaobject id="testlink_logo">
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata 
				    align="center" 
				    fileref="../media/testlink_logo.png" 
				    contentwidth="200px" 
				    format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</para>
	
	<para>In TestLink you have, among other features, Test Plans, Requirement 
	management, Baselines, Custom Fields, Test Suite with Test Cases and 
	Reporting. For external access, there is an XML-RPC API available (it is 
	not enabled by default). Other two nice features in TestLink are the 
	versioning of the some entities, like Test Case and Requirements, and the 
	ability to import and export data in different formats.</para>
	
	<para>There are bindings for the TestLink XML-RPC API available for Java, 
	Perl, PHP, Ruby and other programming languages. The integration between 
	Jenkins and TestLink is done using TestLink Java API - 
	<ulink url="http://testlinkjavaapi.sourceforge.net">
	http://testlinkjavaapi.sourceforge.net</ulink>.</para>
	
	<para>
		<mediaobject id="testlink_001_01">
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata 
				    align="center" 
				    fileref="../media/testlink_001.png" 
				    width="100%" 
				    contentdept="100%" 
				    format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</para>
	
	<para>At the moment that this guide is being written the latest version of 
	TestLink is <emphasis>1.9.3</emphasis>. While the Jenkins version is not a 
	big issue for this integration, the same cannot be said about TestLink. 
	This guide is intended for Testlink 1.9.3 XML-RPC API. In case there are 
	other versions available at the moment that you are reading this guide, 
	please consult the 
	<ulink url="http://wiki.jenkins-ci.org/display/JENKINS/TestLink+Plugin">
	plug-in Wiki</ulink> for further information on this.</para>
	
	<para>TestLink is licensed under the GPL License and its code is hosted at 
	gitorious - 
	<ulink url="http://www.gitorious.org/testlink-ga/testlink-code">
	http://www.gitorious.org/testlink-ga/testlink-code</ulink>.</para>
	
</chapter>