<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="chapter.4">

    <title>TestLink Configuration</title>

    <section>

        <title>Installing TestLink</title>

        <para>In this part of the tutorial we will show how to install and
        configure TestLink. Let's start by downloading
        <emphasis>testlink-1.9.3.tar.gz</emphasis> from
        <ulink url="http://www.teamst.org">http://www.teamst.org</ulink>.
        Decompress it with <command>tar -zxvf testlink-1.9.3.tar.gz</command>.
        Move the directory created to your HTTP server root directory and open
        <ulink url="http://localhost/testlink-1.9.3">
        http://localhost/testlink-1.9.3</ulink> in your browser.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_002">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_002.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_003">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_003.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>Now the installation wizard will guide you through the rest of
        the installation. But before going on, we need to create a database in
        MySQL.</para>

        <para><command>mysql> create database testlink;</command></para>

        <para>The next step is to create a user that TestLink will use to
        access the database.</para>

        <para>
        <command>mysql> grant all privileges on testlink.* to 'testlink' identified by 'testlink';</command>
        </para>

        <para><command>mysql> flush privileges;</command></para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_004">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_004.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_005">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_005.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_006">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_006.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>If everything worked out correctly you should be asked to log in
        with user admin and password admin. The examples in this tutorial
        require you to have a user with administrator rights in TestLink.</para>

        <para>By default, the XML-RPC comes disabled in TestLink. Let's enable
        it by editing config.inc.php, located in TestLink root folder.</para>

        <para>
          <command>$tlCfg->api->enabled = TRUE;</command>
        </para>

        <para>Finally, let's make sure that the attachments retrieved from the
        database are ordered by its ID. This way, the order of attachments will
        be preserved in TestLink. We could use the date that the attachment was
        inserted in database, however the precision of the date_added column is
        in seconds, what could lead to inconsistencies in the way that
        attachments are displayed in TestLink.</para>

        <para>
          <command>$g_attachments->order_by = " ORDER BY id ASC ";</command>
        </para>

    </section>

    <section>

        <title>Creating a Test Project</title>

        <para>When you log in by the first time in TestLink it is showed to you
        a form to create a Test Project. After creating a test project you will
        be able to create test plans, requirements, specify and execute your
        tests.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_007">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_007.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>Create a test project with name My first project, prefix MFP and
        make sure the following options are checked: Enable Requirements
        feature, Enable Testing Priority, Enable Test Automation (API keys),
        Enable Inventory, Active and Public. Click on Create button.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_008">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_008.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>If the following screen is not displayed, review your previous
        steps or consult TestLink documentation for further assistance.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_009">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_009.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

    </section>

    <section>

        <title>Creating and assigning a Custom Field</title>

        <para>Click on the Project item of the top menu to be redirected to the
        main screen. Now we will create the custom field used for automation.
        The plug-in uses this custom field's value to link a test case in
        TestLink with a test result from your Jenkins build.</para>

        <para>Click on Define Custom Fields under the Test Project options box.
        Now create a custom field using the name Java Class, label
        Java Class, available for Test Case, type string, enable on Test Spec
        Design and display on test execution No. The plug-in retrieves the
        custom fields by its name and not by the value in its label.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_010">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_010.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_011">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_011.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>The last step now is to assign this custom field to be used in
        our test project. Go back to the main screen and click on Assign Custom
        Fields. It will take you to a screen with the list of the available
        custom fields. Select the Java Class custom field and click on the
        Assign button.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_012">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_012.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

    </section>

    <section>

        <title>Specifying Test Suite and Test Cases</title>

        <para>For those who work with tests this part may be slightly easier
        than the previous sections. What we are going to do now is to create a
        test suite and some test cases. In TestLink your test cases are kept
        under a test suite which is, by its turn, under a test project.</para>

        <para>Back to the main screen, in the top menu you will see the option
        Test Specification. Click on this option. The test specification
        screen is quite simple. On the left you have the navigator, with the
        settings, filter and the tree of test suites and test cases. Start
        clicking on your test project to see the test suite operations
        available.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_013">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_013.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>Create a test suite with any name that you want. This field is
        not important for this tutorial. Once created, your test suite will be
        displayed in the tree on the left. Now click on the test suite in the
        tree to see the available test case operations.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_014">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_014.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>Create a test case with any title or summary. The important
        information on this screen for the automation are the execution type
        and the Java class (custom field created in the previous step). In
        execution type select Automated and for Java class fill with the
        java class jenkins.plugins.testlink.examples.TestCurrentTime (present in
        the example project).</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_015">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_015.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_016">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_016.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_017">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_017.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_018">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_018.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

    </section>

    <section>

        <title>Create a Test Plan and add the Test Cases</title>

        <para>This is the last step for the TestLink configuration. However
        before we start this step, there is an important concept in TestLink:
        Builds.</para>

        <para>In TestLink, you create a test plan outlining how you will test
        your application under test. Once you have a test plan you can start to
        add test cases to your test plan, and then execute the test plan.</para>

        <para>A build in TestLink can be seen as the execution of a test plan.
        Once the test plan is executed you are not allowed to edit the test
        cases of this test plan (it wouldn't be right to change the scope or
        exit criteria of a test case after it had already been executed).</para>

        <para>Go back to the main screen and click on the Test Plan Management
        option available under the Test Plan box on the right of the screen.
        Create a test plan with the name My first test plan, any description
        and make sure that Active and Public are checked.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_019">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_019.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_020">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_020.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>In the last box on the right of the screen, click on Add / Remove
        Test Cases and add the test case that you created to your test plan.</para>

        <para>
            <mediaobject id="testlink_021">
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata
                       align="center"
                       fileref="../media/testlink_021.png"
                       width="100%"
                       contentdept="100%"
                       format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </para>

        <para>Create a Build in TestLink is optional, as the plug-in
        automatically creates a new build if there is none with the name that
        you provided in the Jenkins job configuration page. When you go back
        to your test plan, you should see more options available in the Test
        Plan box and two other boxes: Test Execution and Test Plan contents,
        as well as other options available in the top menu.</para>

        <para>We are done with TestLink for now, the next step is to configure
        Jenkins.</para>

    </section>

</chapter>