<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="chapter.7">

	<title>Strategies to find Test Results</title>
	
	<para>After your automated tests are executed the plug-in has to look for 
	<emphasis>Test Results</emphasis>. This way it will know whether an 
	automated test was executed correctly or not and then it can update the 
	test execution status in TestLink.</para>
	
	<para>Jenkins TestLink Plug-in uses three strategies to find Test Results: 
	<emphasis>TAP</emphasis>, <emphasis>TestNG</emphasis> and 
	<emphasis>JUnit</emphasis>. All these strategies use a key custom field to 
	associate a test result in Jenkins with an automated test case in 
	TestLink.</para>
	
	<section>
	
		<title>JUnit</title>
    
        <para>The plug-in scans the JUnit test results twice. The first time 
        it matches the key custom field value against the JUnit suite name, and 
        in its second turn it matches the key custom field value against the 
        JUnit <emphasis>class name or test name</emphasis>.</para>
        
        <para>The reason why the plug-in needs to use either the class or the 
        test name is that the JUnit format is used by many different tools, 
        without having a de facto DTD or XML Schema document. First the plug-in 
        tries to use the class name. If it is empty, the plug-in uses the test 
        name.</para>

        <para>
            <programlisting language="xml">
<![CDATA[<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<testsuite failures="1" time="0.078" errors="0" skipped="0" tests="1" name="A Suite">
  <testcase time="0" classname="tcA" name="testVoid">
    <failure type="junit.framework.AssertionFailedError" message="null">junit....</failure>
  </testcase>
  <testcase time="0" classname="tcB" name="testVoid" />
  <testcase time="0" classname="tcC" name="testVoid" />
  <testcase time="0" name="nameA" />
  <testcase time="0" name="nameB" />
</testsuite>]]>
            </programlisting>
        </para>

		<para>In the example above, we have a test suite which failed, and five 
		test cases, where only one failed. Let's suppose you created this test 
		suite to execute an automated test case from TestLink. This would mean 
		that you have a test case in TestLink with a custom field which value 
		is <emphasis>A Suite</emphasis> (we assume you are using this custom 
		field as key in the job configuration). The plug-in, after scanning the 
		test results, it will update your test execution status to 
		<emphasis>Failed</emphasis> in TestLink, because the test suite has 
		failed.</para>
		
		<para>Now, suppose you created many test cases for your automated 
		test cases from TestLink, and tcB is the value of your key custom 
		field in TestLink. Then the plug-in will update the test case execution 
		status to <emphasis>Passed</emphasis>, as this test case hasn't failed.
		</para>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
	
		<title>TestNG</title>

        <para>The strategy used for TestNG is quite similar to the JUnit one. 
        The plug-in scans the test results twice, also matching the key custom 
        field value against the TestNG suite name and then against each TestNG 
        class name.</para>

		<para>
		  <programlisting language="xml">
<![CDATA[<testng-results>
  <reporter-output>
  </reporter-output>
  <suite name="Command line suite" duration-ms="0" started-at="2010-11-17T13:31:41Z" finished-at="2010-11-17T13:31:41Z">
    <groups>
    </groups>
    <test name="Command line test" duration-ms="0" started-at="2010-11-17T13:31:41Z" finished-at="2010-11-17T13:31:41Z">
      <class name="br.eti.kinoshita.Test">
        <test-method status="FAIL" signature="testVoid()" name="testVoid" duration-ms="0" started-at="2010-11-17T13:31:41Z" finished-at="2010-11-17T13:31:41Z">
        </test-method>
      </class>
    </test>
  </suite>
</testng-results>]]>
		  </programlisting>
		</para>
		
		<para>In the above example, we have a test suite named <emphasis>
		Command line suite</emphasis>, and a class which name is <emphasis>
		br.eti.kinoshita.Test</emphasis>. You could have a key custom field 
		in TestLink which value was the test suite name or the class name. 
		In this case, both situations would lead to the test execution status 
		in TestLink being updated to <emphasis>Failed</emphasis>. The TestNG 
		test suite status is defined by its tests status, while the class 
		status is defined by its status attribute.</para>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
	
		<title>TAP - Test Anything Protocol</title>

		<para>Lastly, we have TAP. Here the plug-in simply utilizes the TAP 
		file name as option to match it against the key custom field value. If 
		the TAP file contains any <emphasis>Bail out!</emphasis>, 
		<emphasis>not ok</emphasis> or <emphasis>TODO directive</emphasis>, 
		then the test execution status is updated to <emphasis>
		Failed</emphasis> in TestLink. If the TAP file contains any 
		<emphasis>SKIP directive</emphasis> then the plug-in updates the test 
		execution status to <emphasis>Blocked</emphasis>. Otherwise, the plug-in 
		considers that the test must be marked as <emphasis>Passed</emphasis>.
		</para>
		
		<para>
		  <programlisting>
<![CDATA[1..3
ok 1 testOk
ok 2
not ok 3]]>
		  </programlisting>
		</para>
		
		<para>The example above shows a <emphasis>TAP Stream</emphasis> (that 
		was stored in a file), which has three test results, and one of the 
		failed. Hence the test execution status will be updated as 
		<emphasis>Failed</emphasis> in TestLink.</para>
		
		<para>Using TAP, you can define the Platform (defined in TestLink) that 
		you used for your tests or extra attachments to be uploaded to 
		TestLink. These topics are covered in <xref linkend="chapter.9" />.</para>
	
	</section>
	
</chapter>