<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="chapter.7">

	<title>Strategies for finding Test Results</title>
	
	<para>After your automated tests are executed the plug-in has to look for 
	<emphasis>Test Results</emphasis>. This way it will know whether an 
	automated test was executed correctly or not and then update the test status 
	in <application>TestLink</application>.</para>
	
	<para><application>Jenkins TestLink Plug-in</application> currently has 
	three strategies for finding Test Results: <emphasis>TAP</emphasis>, 
	<emphasis>TestNG</emphasis> and <emphasis>JUnit</emphasis>. All these three 
	strategies uses a key custom field to associate a test result with an 
	automated test case.</para>
	
	<section>
	
		<title><application>JUnit</application></title>

		<para>For <application>JUnit</application>, the plug-in uses the name 
		of the test suite. If the test suite name is the same as the value of 
		the key custom field of a test case, then the plug-in checks if failures or 
		errors attributes of the testsuite are greater than 0 (zero). 
		If so, the test case is updated with the status failed. 
		Otherwise it is updated with passed.</para>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
	
		<title><application>TestNG</application></title>

		<para>For <application>TestNG</application>, the plug-in uses the 
		class name of the test as key. Usually a <application>TestNG</application> 
		<acronym>XML</acronym> report contains a suite with many tests. 
		The plug-in looks for the name of the classes of the tests. If a 
		<application>TestNG</application> class name is the same as the value 
		of the key custom field of a test case, then the plug-in checks the 
		status of the methods of the class. If a class contains a method that 
		failed, then the test case is updated with the status failed. 
		Otherwise it is updated with passed.</para>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
	
		<title><acronym>TAP</acronym></title>

		<para>For <acronym>TAP</acronym>, the plug-in uses the <acronym>TAP</acronym> 
		file name as key. If the <acronym>TAP</acronym> file name is the same 
		as the value of the key custom field of a test case, 
		then the plug-in checks whether the <acronym>TAP</acronym> file 
		contains errors (not ok). If so, the test case is updated in 
		<application>TestLink</application> with the status failed. 
		Otherwise it is updated with passed.</para>
	
	</section>
	
</chapter>