<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter lang="pt_br" version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
         xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
         xmlns:ns5="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
         xmlns:ns4="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
         xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
         xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
	<title>An Introduction to TestLink</title>
	
	<para>TestLink is an open source test management tool written in PHP. 
	In order to install TestLink you will need a Apache or similar http server 
	with PHP 5 and a database. The databases currently supported by TestLink 
	out of the box are MySQL, Postgre SQL and MS SQL, although there are 
	users that managed to use Oracle too. You can download it from 
	http://www.teamst.org.</para>
	
	<para>In TestLink you have, among other features, Test Plans, Requirement 
	management, Baselines, Custom Fields, Test Suite with Test Cases and 
	Reporting. For external access, there is a XML-RPC API available 
	(it is not enabled by default). Other two nice features in TestLink are the 
	versioning of the some entities, like Test Case and Requirements, 
	and the ability to import and export your testing data in different formats.</para>
	
	<para>There are bindings for the TestLink XML-RPC API available for other 
	languages such as Ruby and Java. The Jenkins and TestLink integration is 
	done using the Java API (http://testlinkjavaapi.sourceforge.net).</para>
	
	<para>At the moment that this guide is being written the latest stable 
	version of TestLink is 1.9.2, however versions 1.9.3 and 2.0 are already 
	planned and scheduled. While Jenkins version is not a compatibility for 
	this integration, the same cannot be said about TestLink. This guide is 
	intended for Testlink 1.9.2. In case there are other versions available at 
	the moment that you are reading this guide, you may find issues during your 
	Job execution. There is a compatibility table available in the plug-in Wiki.</para>
	
	<para>TestLink is licensed under the GPL License and its code is hosted 
	at gitorious (http://www.gitorious.org/testlink-ga/testlink-code).</para>
	
</chapter>